SHUBHAM BAROLIA

9164763210 | baro21shubham@gmail.com | Muzaffarpur, Bihar

Summary

Highly focused Data Analyst with 4+ years experience position. Experienced in interpreting and analyzing of data to drive growth for business. Expertise in extracting insights, developing dashboards, and performing trend analysis to support business decisions.

Experience

NTT DATA | Bengaluru, Kamataka Data Analyst II | 02/2023 - Present

- Led analysis of accounts receivable data for Konika, a top provider of printers and related products. Data has been fetched from SQL server Database.
- Utilized Information from the company's accounting system including payment due dates, total amounts owed etc and data exploration, data cleaning has been done using Python (Pandas)
- Created and delivered **Dashboards in Power BI** on Aging, Revenue, Profit, DSO and Collections for Finance Team cutting the timing from 40 hours to 6 hours, reduced processing time by 85%.
- Deployed SCD 2 for multiple master files within the FCC Team to manage version control.
- Implemented calculations to determine the payment aging, aiding in enhanced credit control and optimized cash flow management.

Bengaluru, KA Data Analyst | 01/2020 - 02/2023

- Fetching data and analyzing data using SQL, Python and Excel presenting it to leadership team.
 Examines new ad hoc requests from client and formulate data according to that.
- Showing the monthly and weekly data trends of SLA's. Also to keep track KPI's for different Accounts.
- Worked on various reports, Design and develop dashboards using SQL and Excel.
- Experience in Creating, Analysing and communicating business insights from data.
- Experience in **Statistical Techniques and EDA** and features engineering to find out the relationship between various columns and able to do storytelling in front of clients.

R-Prime Technology

Internship | 03/2019 - 05/2019

Achievements/Tasks Learnt data analysing techniques using R, Python and SQL Analysis of Titanic Data sets from Kaggle using Numpy and Pandas Plotted graphs using Matplotlib

Skills

Python, MySQL, MS SSMS (Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio), Statistics, Power BI, Pandas, Numpy, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Jupyter, Data Analysis, Data Cleaning, VScode, Snowflake

Education

JSS Academy of Technical Education | Bengaluru, Kamataka B.Tech/B.E. in Information Science and Engineering | 08/2019

St. Xavier's Jr. Sr. School | Muzaffarpur, Bihar Class XII | 06/2015

Certificates

NTT DATA Data Analyst grade 4, Completion Internship Certificate - Data Science